A few days ago, I shared a simple background remover tool on Reddit.
While many liked the simplicity, one user, Adventurous,
date 9971, pointed out something crucial. In the real world, especially for e-commerce
sellers and photographers, it's not just about the AI model, it's about the workflow.
They mentioned that using tools like GIMP with PYAutoGUI was a nightmare.
So, I decided to fix the pain points they mentioned.
Today, I am updating the BG underscore remover with a focus on professional utility.
First, the tool now mirrors your entire folder structure.
If you drop a folder with 10 subdirectories, the output will look exactly the same,
preserving your organization. Second, I've ensured that original
file names are kept intact to avoid confusion in product management.
Third, I added a Review Needed feature. If the AI is unsure about a cutout,
it automatically moves that file to a separate folder for manual inspection,
saving you from hunting through hundreds of images.
Finally, as a developer who loves data, I've integrated a local log that tracks
processing time and hardware performance. This helps you see if switching to a dedicated GPU
actually makes a difference for your specific batch.
The updated source code is available on my GitHub.
If you find this workflow improvement helpful, please consider leaving a star on the repository.
Your conscientious support is what keeps this project evolving.